Welcome to this course on ChatGPT Prompt Engineering for Developers
欢迎学习《面向开发者的 ChatGPT Prompt 工程》课程
I'm thrilled to have with me Iza Fulford to teach this along with me
很高兴能邀请到 Isa Fulford 和我一起授课
She is a member of the technical staff of OpenAI and had built the popular
她是 OpenAI 的技术人员之一，曾建立了流行的
ChatGPT Retrieval plugin and a large part of her work has been teaching people
ChatGPT 检索插件，她大部分工作是教人们
how to use LLM or large language model technology in products
如何在产品中使用OEM或大语言模型技术
She's also contributed to the OpenAI cookbook that teaches people prompting
她还为OpenAI手册做出了贡献，教会人们如何使用提示
So thrilled to have you with you
所以，很高兴有你参与
And I'm thrilled to be here and share some prompting best practices with you all
我也很高兴能在这里与大家分享一些提示的最佳实践
So there's been a lot of material on the internet for prompting with articles
在互联网上有很多关于提示资料以及一些文章
like 30 prompts everyone has to know
比如，每个人都必须知道的30个提示
A lot of that has been focused on the ChatGPT web user interface
许多人正在使用 ChatGPT 的 Web 用户界面
which many people are using to do specific and often one-off tasks
来完成特定而且通常是一次性的任务
But I think the power of LLMs, large language models as a developer too
但作为一名开发者，我认为OEMs和大语言模型的强大也是不可忽视的
that is using API calls to LLMs to quickly build software applications
那就是通过API调用OEM来快速构建软件应用程序
I think that is still very underappreciated
我认为这仍然被严重低估
In fact, my team at AI Fund, which is a sister company to Deep Learning.AI
事实上，我在AI Fund的团队，也就是Deep Learning.AI的姐妹公司
has been working with many startups on applying these technologies
一直在与许多初创公司、不同项目合作
to many different applications
来应用这些技术
And it's been exciting to see what LLM APIs can enable developers
看到OEM API能够让开发者快速建立一些东西
to very quickly build
这很令人兴奋
So in this course, we'll share with you some of the possibilities
所以在这个课程中，我们将与你分享一些可能性
for what you can do as well as best practices for how you can do them
你可以做什么，以及如何做的最佳实践
There's a lot of material to cover
这里会覆盖很多资料
First, you'll learn some prompting best practices for software development
首先，你将学习一些软件开发的提示词最佳实践
Then we'll cover some common use cases, summarizing, inferring
然后，我们将涵盖一些常见的用例、总结、推断
transforming, expanding, and then you'll build a chatbot using an LLM
转化、扩展，然后使用LLM建立一个聊天机器人
We hope that this will spark your imagination about new applications
我们希望这将激发你
that you can build
开发新应用的想象力
So in the development of large language models or LLMs
因此，在大型语言模型或LLM的发展中
there have been broadly two types of LLMs, which I'm going to refer to
大体上有两种类型的LLM，我把它们称为
as base LLMs and instruction-tuned LLMs
基础LLM和指令学习LLM
So base LLM has been trained to predict the next word based on text training data
基础LLM已经被训练成基于文本训练数据来预测下一个单词
often trained on a large amount of data from the internet and other sources
通常通过互联网和其他来源训练大量数据
to figure out what's the next most likely word to follow
并计算出下一个最可能出现的词是什么
So for example, if you were to prompt this, once upon a time there was a unicorn
比如，你输入这个提示："从前有一只独角兽"
it may complete this, that is, it may predict the next several words are
它会进行补全，并预测接下来的几个词是
that live in a magical forest with all unicorn friends
"和所有独角兽朋友一起生活在一个神奇的森林里"
But if you were to prompt this with what is the capital of France
但是如果你是用"法国的首都是什么"作为提示
then based on what articles on the internet might have
那么根据互联网上的文章
it's quite possible that the base LLM will complete this with
很有可能是，基础LLM会以下列方式完成这个任务
what is France's largest city, what is France's population, and so on
什么是法国最大的城市，什么是法国的人口，等等
because articles on the internet could quite plausibly be lists of quiz questions
因为互联网上的文章，可能会列出
about the country of France
关于法国的小测验问题列表
In contrast, an instruction-tuned LLM, which is where a lot of momentum
与此相反，指令学习LLM，发展势头较猛
of LLM research and practice has been going
LLM的研究和实践一直在进行
an instruction-tuned LLM has been trained to follow instructions
一个经过指令学习的LLM已经被训练得能够遵循指令
So if you were to ask it, what is the capital of France
因此，如果你问它，法国的首都是什么？
it's much more likely to output something like the capital of France is Paris
它很可能输出法国的首都是巴黎
So the way that instruction-tuned LLMs are typically trained is
因此，指令学习的LLM的典型训练方式是
you start off with a base LLM that's been trained on a huge amount of text data
从一个在大量文本数据上训练过的基础LLM开始
and further train it, further fine-tune it with inputs and outputs
然后进一步训练它，用输入和输出来进一步微调它
that are instructions and good attempts to follow those instructions
这些输入和输出都是指令，也是遵循这些指令的良好尝试
and then often further refine using a technique called RLHF
然后经常使用一种叫做RLHF的技术进一步完善
reinforcement learning from human feedback, to make the system better able
从人类反馈中进行强化学习，以使系统能够更好地
to be helpful and follow instructions
提供帮助并遵循指令
Because instruction-tuned LLMs have been trained to be helpful
因为经过指令学习的LLM已经被训练得很有帮助
honest, and harmless, so for example, they're less likely to output
诚实且无害，因此，举例来说，它们不太可能输出
problematic text, such as toxic outputs, compared to base LLM
那些与基础LLM相比，会出问题的文本，如有害的输出
a lot of the practical usage scenarios have been shifting
很多实际应用场景已经开始向
toward instruction-tuned LLMs
指令学习LLM转移
Some of the best practices you find on the internet may be more suited
你在互联网上找到的一些最佳实践可能更适用于基础LLM
for a base LLM, but for most practical applications today
但对于今天的大多数实际应用情况来说，它们可能不太合适
we would recommend most people instead focus on instruction-tuned LLMs
我们建议大多数人多关注指令学习LLM
which are easier to use, and also because of the work of OpenAI
它们更容易使用，而且由于OpenAI
and other LLM companies, becoming safer and more aligned
和其他LLM公司的工作，也将变得更加安全和一致
So this course will focus on best practices for instruction-tuned LLMs
因此，本课程将重点介绍指令学习LLM的最佳实践
which is what we recommend you use for most of your applications
这也是我们建议你在大多数应用中使用的
Before moving on, I just want to acknowledge the team from OpenAI
在继续之前，我想感谢来自OpenAI
and DeepLearning.ai that had contributed to the materials
和DeepLearning.ai的团队
that Isa and I will be presenting
他们为我和Isa将要介绍的资料做出了贡献
I'm very grateful to Andrew Main, Joe Palermo, Boris Power
我非常感谢Andrew Main, Joe Palermo, Boris Power
Ted Sanders, and Lilian Wang from OpenAI that were very involved
Ted Sanders，以及来自OpenAI的Lilian Wang
with us brainstorming materials, vetting the materials to put together
与我们一起集思广益，审核资料
the curriculum for this short course
并做成这个简短的课程
And I'm also grateful on the DeepLearning side for the work
我也很感谢DeepLearning方面的工作
of Jeff Ludwig, Eddie Hsu, and Tommy Nelson
Jeff Ludwig、Eddie Hsu和Tommy Nelson的工作
So when you use an instruction-tuned LLM, think of giving instructions
因此，当你使用一个指令学习LLM时，可以将其看作是
to another person, say someone that's smart but doesn't know
向另一个人发出指令，比如一个聪明但不知道
the specifics of your task
任务细节的人
So when an LLM doesn't work, sometimes it's because the instructions
因此，当一个LLM不工作时，有时是因为指令
weren't clear enough
不够清楚
For example, if you were to say, please write me something
例如，如果你说，请给我写一些
about Alan Turing
关于艾伦-图灵的东西
Well, in addition to that, it can be helpful to be clear about
那么，除此之外，明确以下几点也会有所帮助
whether you want the text to focus on his scientific work
你想让文章侧重于他的科学工作
or his personal life or his role in history or something else
他的个人生活、他在历史上的作用或其他方向
And if you specify what you want the tone of the text to be
如果你指定了想要文本的语调
should it take on the tone like a professional journalist would write
它是否会根据指定的语调来写，比如像专业记者写的那样
or is it more of a casual note that you dash off to a friend?
还是更像随手写给朋友的轻松语气？
That holds
这一点是成立的
The LLM generates what you want
LLM会产生你想要的东西
And of course, if you picture yourself asking, say
当然，如果你想象是自己在问，比如
a fresh college graduate to carry out this task for you
一个刚毕业的大学生为你完成这项任务
if you can even specify what snippets of text they should read
如果你甚至可以指定他们应该阅读哪些文本片段
in advance to write this text about Alan Turing
提前写出这篇关于艾伦-图灵的文章
then that even better sets up that fresh college grad for success
那么，这能成功让那个刚毕业的大学生
to carry out this task for you
更好的为你完成这项任务
So in the next video, you see examples of how to be clear
因此，在接下来的视频中，你会看到如何清晰且明确
and specific, which is an important principle of prompting LLMs
描述提示，这是一个重要的LLM提示准则
And you also learn from Isa a second principle of prompting
而且你还将从Isa那里学到了第二个提示词准则
that is giving a LLM time to think
那就是给LLM时间来思考
So with that, let's go on to the next video
因此，让我们继续观看下一个视频